Farewell, Earth
The ship that is departing is
The Space Battleship
Yamato
It departs now to Iscandar,
at the end of the cosmos,
bearing its fate.
"We will come back, no matter what it takes"
Answer with a smile to the waving people
Going far from the Galaxy towards Iscandar
A faint gleam of hope
The Space Battleship Yamato
Captain's Log:
On Leptapoda, the planet where we landed to resupply, we learned a surprising fact.
The Yamato's final destination, Iscandar, which we'd thought a planet of hope,
is the twin planet of the enemy world, Garmillas.
The two share a connection about which we were not informed.
The Garmillans hold Iscandar to be an object of worship.
We met with a high-ranking Garmillas official,
Admiral Ditz, who'd been imprisoned on Leptapoda.
He and his comrades were rebelling
against the current leader of Garmillas.
But given our relationship, quickly putting differences aside was impossible.
That said, we did gain several useful
pieces of information about Garmillas.
Their leader's name was Abelt Desler.
He ruled over his vast, interstellar empire with a terrible iron fist.
Admiral Ditz and his forces left for the other prison planets,
intending to free the rest.
We were forced to part ways.
But even if they would not fight with us, they left a liaison.
I would like to believe that this will lead to a future of hope.
Furthermore, our ship's Operations Officer, kidnapped by the enemy,
was confirmed to be alive.
According to Mrs. Domel, who had made contact with her,
the Garmillans believed her to be Yurisha...
Pause
Not yet... Just a little longer.
Welcome, Yurisha, to Great Garmillas.
I am honored to receive you.
You haven't forgotten me, have you?
What's going on here?
She's insisting on being allowed aboard a Falcon...
And he keeps saying he can't allow it.
Of course I can't!
Melda, what is your mission?
I am here as a liaison.
Do your duties as a liaison involve one of the Yamato's fighters?
They do not.
There you have it, then.
Very well, I will obey.
So you'll listen to Kodai?
Don't we have something she could pilot?
There's the one I used on Balun.
What are you talking about?
I'll let you take care of it.
Hey! You're leaving?
Squad 5, give a status report. After reporting, begin loading secondary armaments.
I see... A captured ship.
Are you sure about this? You'll be shooting at your own people.
That will depend on you.
The Yamato's mission is to reach Iscandar.
Not to go to Garmillas and fight.
Or do you want to destroy us out of a desire for revenge?
That isn't true...
It isn't true anymore, right?
Rud Iscandar.
Right? It isn't, right?
I'm glad you're here... I've been meaning to ask you something!
Hey, don't point your finger at one from Iscandar!
I don't mind. It doesn't bother me.
But...
Why didn't you tell us Iscandar and Garmillas were at the same place?
If you'd known, would you have come? Or wouldn't you have?
What would we have done if we'd known?
Would we have still been able to
maintain our desire to go to Iscandar?
I think we made it this far because we didn't know.
But I was surprised that they're neighbors.
Melda says that Mori is probably on the Garmillas home planet.
She's probably being treated well.
If they still believe she's Yurisha.
The moon here is big... Big and beautiful.
That isn't the moon.
You didn't know?
That is Iscandar.
When did you guess?
I wasn't certain until just now.
I see...
What will you do?
My duty is to protect you.
Here.
Thank you.
You may leave, Hilde.
Rud Iscandar.
That girl is the same race as the boy outside.
Her father died in battle with a barbarian ship.
Called the Yamato, I believe.
I wasn't born on this planet, either.
But she and I are both Garmillans.
Do you know who you are?
I am Yurisha of Iscandar.
No, you are not.
Now you are Yurisha of Garmillas. You are a bird in a cage.
A mere pawn to use against Iscandar.
"The salvation of all intelligent life in the universe."
Your sister's little speech.
It's easy for her, isn't it? She does nothing but test others.
However, our leader is different.
He's trying to build a civilization that spans galaxies.
He isn't like that woman, who refuses to even dirty her own hands.
Only under imperial protection can eternal peace be possible.
That is true salvation.
And he can make it a reality.
I heard you stopped at that prison planet.
How was it?
It was awful.
When I was a child, I was sent there.
Simply because I wasn't Garmillan.
And he saved us with his own hands.
We, who were of another race.
Do you love him?
I'm sorry...
Only, that's such an odd question to hear from an Iscandarian princess.
Do I love him?
This is the best tea, from Melan.
Drink before it gets cold.
Today, we will attend General Domel's memorial ceremony.
The 5th Colonization Planning Group  meeting has been moved to Hall 6.
My lord, the invincible Goer fleet's 3,000  ships are heading directly to Garmillas.
But it will take a minimum of two months.
We are working night and day to see you as soon as possible...
Enough, Goer, Just do your best.
Yes, sir! Ghale Desler!
The Yamato is entering our last line of defense.
It's knocking on the door of the Salezar System.
I'm told the Yamato has a gun with the power to destroy planets.
The question is how to react, with our
defensive fleets almost entirely absent.
There is no need for worry. I've held a powerful fleet in reserve.
The Imperial Guard, not the army, will defend its home planet.
My lord, I would like you to hear something.
What is it?
That girl is not Yurisha.
I believe her to be a Terron.
Are you certain?
I caught a glimpse of something.
Witch.
Is that an issue?
Whether she's real is irrelevant.
The Third Princess of Iscandar has approved the great unification.
And as long as the people believe that...
I understand. You're correct.
It's time for the ceremony, everyone.
Elk Domel, hero to the people and my dear friend.
Your loss tears at my heart...
I believe my beloved citizens feel the same way.
But sadness will not bring him back.
What will fill the void he left? Only one thing...
Hope!
Hope will heal our sadness, and guide the way to our future!
I don't see Minister Talan.
Our lord has ordered him elsewhere.
Indeed... They were such friends, I'm sorry to hear that.
I shall give you hope!
The dream of our people, our great destiny...
Our great hope, the unification of Garmillas and Iscandar!
In the distant past, our people were divided in two.
Now it is time for us to become one again.
The Third Princess of Iscandar, Yurisha, has approved this!
Yurisha?
My people, let us move forward to our hope, the great unification!
Let us move into the future!
The endless march of Garmillas,
toward the future, is what my friend Domel would have desired!
Ghale Garmillan!
Ghale Iscandar!
Ghale Desler!
Ghale Phuzeron!
This strategy you've proposed...
I cannot agree to the last part.
You're kidding, right?
Operations Officer Mori Rescue Plan
No, I can't permit it.
Why? But you...
The Yamato's goal is Iscandar.
Not Garmillas.
A-Are you serious?
Then what happens to her? Do we let her die?
Garmillas is right next to Iscandar.
There's time for him to rethink it.
To be honest...
Captain, you...
I know.
But we've made it this far.
You're right.
That's true.
Working with those Garmillans just because they're fighting their government...
I don't know what the higher-ups are thinking.
But isn't that Melda person an ally?
You're being naïve!
It's possible Iscandar and Garmillas are working together to trick us.
I don't want to consider it, but yeah.
Hey, look!
Celebrate reaching the Large Magellanic with a
Magellan
Parfait!
I see.
He's doing that poorly?
No, no, no! We have a duty to confidentiality!
You can't tell everyone, Sabu!
I know that.
You can't, Sabu...
We'll keep the confidentiality.
H-Hey...
D-Don't get the wrong idea!
It's the wrong idea?!
She called him "Sabu."
Do you not have one? Someone like that?
No one's asking you!
I do.
Eh?! Who? Is it Kodai?
No way... Not a chance. S-So who is it?
They are not here.
Oh, they're on Iscandar?
You're being rude, asking so many questions!
Won't you eat, Melda?
It's good.
Well... I...
Hey, are you sure this is food?
Magellan Parfait. It's a popular dessert on board.
You won't eat?
O-Of course!
Well?
I can't believe such a thing existed in this universe...
Isn't that right?
I'm very moved right now!
You have some on you.
Anyway, did you ask about that other thing?
Yeah, I did.
She insists it has to be this colour...
Huh...
I don't understand women...
Yeah.
Is something funny?!
You're so cute, Melda.
You honor me!
You really are cute.
You don't get to say it!
Getting back on topic...
Listen to me!
Is it true you have someone waiting for you on Iscandar?
When I get back, there is something I must tell them.
You're going to confess that you like them?
Hey!
It is not my decision...
Operations Officer Mor
Message from the XO.
At shipboard time 1100, we will enter warp.
Everyone, stand by in type-2 space gear.
Rescue
It's still at eighty percent functionality.
I believe it's a bit early to use it.
I don't mind, Talan. As long as we can use it.
My lord, if I may speak freely, this facility
was meant for when we moved the capital.
It wasn't intended for use against the Yamato.
I said I don't care.
Zar Belk.
The Yamato is coming... They're safe!
They've come a long, long way.
We must greet them properly.
You may stay here and watch.
What is about to happen?
A war.
Crew, Earth is 160,000 light years behind us.
But that is just a number.
Earth is right behind us!
It is right behind us, awaiting your return.
We will soon reach our final objective, the Salezar System.
But the enemy's home planet is there, as well.
It is both our goal and also enemy territory.
But we will choose the path to Iscandar.
Because that is where hope lies.
And because the Earth is behind us, awaiting our return with that hope.
The Yamato will now enter warp,
our last major warp before Iscandar.
All crew will maintain combat status 1 and prepare for warp!
All crew to combat status 1.
Repeat: All crew to combat status 1.
Engines at full power.
Enter warp!
Entering warp!
That's Epidora, fifth planet in the Salezar System.
There is a twin planet in the fourth orbit.
Magnify.
That's Iscandar?
But next to it...
No ships on cosmo radar.
No enemies in a radius of fifty light seconds.
It's quiet.
High energy readings at point L-1 between Garmillas and Iscandar!
Episode 22
The Planet That We Head For
Among the distant stars
Can you hear the wandering souls?
In this galaxy, they can forever rest in peace
Requiem of separation
With this requiem
Sing Along!
Voices sing to praise
An unforgettable memory
And we’ll never forget your name
Farewell friend,
my sorrow
Will not run out
Someday in this sea of stars
Surely
Pray for the Earth!
The oath
Pray for the dream!
The ideal
Last forever!
The enemy unleashes the light of despair upon the Yamato.
Will the Yamato be blown apart just as it reaches its destination?
Overcome this deadly peril and advance, Yamato!
Your goal is the enemy's heart: Desler's Palace.
Next time: One Man's War.
There are 210 days left before humanity is extinct.